learnalberta.ca 2010-06-08

# Privacy Statement - LearnAlberta.ca

### Privacy Statement

## 1\. Our Commitment to Protect Your Personal Information

This page summarizes the privacy policy and practices on the LearnAlberta.ca website in accordance with the standards set out by the Government of Alberta's Cross Government Internet Committee. Alberta Education is committed to providing visitors with a website that respects their privacy. We do not automatically gather any personal information from you, such as your name, address, phone number or e-mail address. This information is only obtained if you supply it voluntarily, usually through contacting us by e-mail or by signing up for a personal account. 

## 2\. Personal Information Management

Any personal information you do provide is managed according to the Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act (Alberta) (“FOIP Act”). This means that, at the point of collection, you will be informed that your personal information is being collected, the purpose for which it is being collected, and a contact person who can answer any questions you may have regarding the collection activity will be identified. We collect only what is necessary for the operation of the website and to respond to your needs. Our use and disclosure of your personal information is limited by the privacy protection provisions of the FOIP Act. When you visit this website, our web server automatically collects a limited amount of standard information essential to the operation and evaluation of the LearnAlberta.ca web site. This information includes:

* the page from which you arrived;
* the date and time of your page request;
* the IP address your computer is using to receive information;
* the type and version of your browser; and
* the name and size of the file you request.

This information helps us assess our information services and is used only for this purpose. It is collected in compliance with the FOIP Act. This information is not used to identify individuals who come to the web site. None of this information is disclosed to third parties including other public bodies, private organizations or persons (“Third Party”).

If you choose to provide your personal information in an e-mail, or by filling out a form with your personal information included and submitting it through our website – Alberta Education will use that information to respond to your message and to help provide you with the information you have requested. E-mails and written correspondence sent to Alberta Education are treated alike – your personal information is not used for any purpose other than to respond to you. Alberta Education will only share the information you provide with another government ministry if your inquiry relates to that ministry. 

Moreover, Alberta Education does not create individual profiles with the information you submit or provide it to any Third Party, nor is your information used for commercial marketing purposes. The personal information you submit is secure once it reaches the government server. In transit between your computer and the server, however, it may not be secure. 

## 3\. Cookies

This website uses cookies. Cookies are small amounts of information that are distributed to web browsers to assist you when you return to this site or a specific area on the site. The cookie used here retains session information, or more specifically, the options selected to determine your itinerary (session cookies remain active only until you close your browser). Alberta Education does not keep a database of information obtained from these cookies. 

## 4\. Security

For site security purposes and to ensure that this service remains available to all users, this government computer system employs software programs to monitor network traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information, or otherwise cause damage. Except for authorized law enforcement investigations, no other attempts are made to identify individual users or their usage habits. 

## 5\. Links to Other Sites

This website contains links to external sites. Alberta Education is not responsible for the content and the privacy practices of other websites, and encourages you to examine each site’s privacy policy and disclaimers in order to make your own decisions regarding the accuracy, reliability and correctness of material and information found there. 

## 6\. Retention of Your Information

Any personal information you are asked to provide via this web site is collected in compliance with the FOIP Act. Only information necessary for the operation of the website and the provision of requested materials or services to you is collected. The information is used only for the purpose it was collected or for a consistent purpose. Furthermore, the information is only retained for the length of time necessary to fulfill the purpose for which it was collected. 

## 7\. Contact Information

For more information about the collection of your personal information, any of the policies described above in relation to our website, please submit your inquiry by visiting our Contact Us page.
